wpmods.com 2017-12-27

# WPHUB Privacy Policy

## Policy summary

## Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  *     * ### Advertising

      * ### Direct Email Marketing (DEM)

Personal Data: Email

    * ### Analytics

      * ### Analytics collected directly and Google Analytics

Personal Data: Cookie and Usage Data

    * ### Backup saving and management

      * ### Vaultpress

Personal Data: Various types of Data

    * ### Contacting the User

      * ### Mailing List or Newsletter

Personal Data: Email, First Name and Last Name

    * ### Displaying content from external platforms

      * ### Google Maps widget

Personal Data: Cookie and Usage Data

    * ### Handling payments

      * ### PayPal

Personal Data: Various types of Data

    * ### Heat mapping

      * ### Crazyegg

Personal Data: Cookie and Usage Data

    * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

      * ### AddThis, Google+ +1 button and social widgets and Twitter Tweet button and social widgets

Personal Data: Cookie and Usage Data

    * ### Location-based interactions

      * ### Geolocation

Personal Data: Geographic position

    * ### Managing email addresses and sending messages

      * ### Freshdesk

Personal Data: Various types of Data

      * ### Mailchimp and Sendgrid

Personal Data: Email

    * ### Registration and authentication

      * ### Direct registration

Personal Data: Address, Country, Email, First Name, Last Name, Password, Phone number and ZIP/Postal code

    * ### Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting

      * ### AdWords Remarketing and Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising

Personal Data: Cookie and Usage Data

    * ### Traffic optimization and distribution

      * ### CloudFlare

Personal Data: Various types of Data

## Further information about Personal Data

  *     * ### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.

The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may concern the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Application depends on the payment system used.

## Contact information

  *     * ### Data owner

WPHUB.com - 16541 Redmond Way Ste 452-C, Redmond WA 98052, [[email protected]](https://www.wphub.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

## Full policy

## Data Controller and Owner

WPHUB.com - 16541 Redmond Way Ste 452-C, Redmond WA 98052,  
[[email protected]](https://www.wphub.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage Data, Email, First Name, Last Name, Phone number, Address, Password, Country, ZIP/Postal code and Geographic position. 

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.  
Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through this Application and declares to have the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Data Controller of all responsibility.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Application to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting, Analytics, Traffic optimization and distribution, Heat mapping, Advertising, Registration and authentication, Managing email addresses and sending messages, Location-based interactions, Displaying content from external platforms, Contacting the User, Handling payments and Backup saving and management. 

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * ### Advertising

These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Application, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

#### Direct Email Marketing (DEM) (This Application)

This Application uses the User Data to propose services and products provided by third parties or unrelated to the product or service provided by this Application.

Personal Data collected: Email. 

  * ### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Analytics collected directly (This Application)

This Application uses an internal analytics system that does not involve third parties.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

#### Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

  * ### Backup saving and management

These services allow the Owner to save and manage backups of this Application on external servers managed by the service provider itself. The backups may include the source code and content as well as the data that the User provides to this Application.

#### Vaultpress (Automattic Inc.)

Vaultpress is a service to save and manage backups provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/)

  * ### Contacting the User

#### Mailing List or Newsletter (This Application)

By registering to the mailing list or to the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after performing a purchase.

Personal Data collected: Email, First Name and Last Name. 

  * ### Displaying content from external platforms

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.  
If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

#### Google Maps widget (Google)

Google Maps is a maps visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Handling payments

Payment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.

#### PayPal (PayPal Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows users to make online payments using their Paypal credentials.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data. 

  * ### Heat mapping

Heat Mapping services are used to display the areas of a page where Users most frequently move the mouse or click. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior.

#### Crazyegg (Crazyegg)

Crazyegg is a heat mapping service provided by Crazy Egg Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy)

  * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### AddThis (Addthis Inc.)

AddThis is a service provided by Clearspring Technologies Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of this Application.  
Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

#### Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

  * ### Location-based interactions

#### Geolocation (This Application)

This Application may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.  
Most browsers and devices provide tools to opt out from this feature by default. If explicit authorization has been provided, the User’s location data may be tracked by this Application.

Personal Data collected: Geographic position. 

  * ### Managing email addresses and sending messages

These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts to communicate with the User via email.  
The services are used to collect data concerning the date and time when the mail is viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacts with incoming mail, such as by clicking on links included in the email.

#### Freshdesk (Freshdesk Inc.)

Freshdesk is a support and contact request management service provided by Freshdesk Inc.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://freshdesk.com/privacy)

#### Mailchimp (Mailchimp)

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by Mailchimp Inc.

Personal Data collected: Email. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

#### Sendgrid (Sendgrid)

Sendgrid is an email address management and message sending service provided by Sendgrid Inc.

Personal Data collected: Email. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://sendgrid.com/email_policy.html)

  * ### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow this Application to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services.  
In this case, this Application will be able to access some Data, stored by these third party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Direct registration (This Application)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to this Application.

Personal Data collected: Address, Country, Email, First Name, Last Name, Password, Phone number and ZIP/Postal code. 

  * ### Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting

These services allow this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

#### AdWords Remarketing (Google)

AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

#### Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google)

Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

  * ### Traffic optimization and distribution

These services allow this Application to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between this Application and the User's browser.  
Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.

#### CloudFlare (Cloudflare)

CloudFlare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by CloudFlare Inc.  
The way CloudFlare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through this Application, i.e., communication between this Application and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from this Application to be collected.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data. 

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy)

## Further information about Personal Data

  * ### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.  
The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may concern the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Application depends on the payment system used.

## Information about Cookies

  * ### Strictly necessary Cookies

These Cookies are necessary for the proper functioning of this Application and are used to store sessions and preferences. 

#### wphub

Used to store preferences of the Application.

#### session_clicks_production

Used to store the User session and keep the User logged in.

  * ### Analytics

These Cookies are necessary for the functioning of the services filed under the section ”Analytics”. 

#### _ut*, _ga

Google Analytics Cookies.

  * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

These Cookies are necessary for the functioning of the services filed under the section ”Interaction with external social networks and platforms”. 

#### __atuvc

AddThis Cookies.

  * ### Other Cookies

#### shown_tours

Determine if user has seen pop-up tutorial

#### wph_saved_themes

Saved theme preferences

Since the installation of third party Cookies and other tracking systems through the services used within this Application can not be technically controlled by the Owner, any specific references to Cookies and tracking systems installed by third parties are to be considered indicative. In order to obtain complete information, consult the privacy policy for the respective third party services listed in this document. 

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.  
The User is aware of the fact that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address). 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. 

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller erase the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda's servers. 

###  Definitions and legal references 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application ), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refer.

#### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers to.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application.

#### This Application

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

#### Cookie

Small piece of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.
